Michal Nawrocki

Fiolkowa 35, Gliwice 44-109, Silesia, Poland +48 571 447 422

michal.m.nawrocki@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/michal-m-nawrocki github.com/michal-nawrocki www.nawrocki.dev

Profile

Recent Computer Science graduate with +4 years of commercial software development experience. Has a big understanding of software development and a passion for self-improvement. Is ready to tackle any problem and continue his self-taught programming journey. Interested in remote offers for engaging and exciting projects.

Skills

- Fast learner
- Responsible
- Fluent in Polish, English, German
- · Good with managing time
- Open to new experiences
- Creative
- Great with working in teams
- Reliable

References

Michal Domagala

Engineering Manager

Flyr, Cracow, PL

linkedin.com/in/michal-domagala-pl

Interests



Gaming



Synthwave Music



Reading



Foreign Languages



Sci-Fi Movies



Cooking



Playing the Guitar

Technical skills

Languages Tools/Platforms

Python, JS, TS, Java, JetBrains, VS Code, Git, Django, DRF, React, SQL, C#, C/C++, Haskell, Docker, Argo, AWS, FastAPI, Flutter, HTML/CSS, Rust Kubernetes, PostgreSQL Flask, SQLAlchemy

Main areas of experience

· Object-oriented programming

Test-driven development

Dockerization/Containers

• Web services infrastructure

Software engineering

Frameworks

• REST APIs

Algorithms

Microservices

Education

MSci Computer Science with an Industrial Year // 2016 - 2021 University of Birmingham, UK

Upper Second-Class Honours (2:1, 3.75 GPA)

Master's Project: Implementing a password manager product that uses voice authentication (Written in Python, Flutter and Google Cloud)

Noticeable modules: Operating Systems, Networks, Network Security,

Mobile computing with Android, Security of Real-World Systems,

Algorithms and Complexity, Intelligent Robotics, Functional Programming

International Baccalaureate Diploma Programme // 2013 - 2016 Zespol Szkol Ogolnokstalcacy nr 10 in Gliwice, Poland

Final Mark - 35 out of 45

Noticeable subjects (out of 7): Computer Science HL (6), Mathematics (5)

Work experience

Software Developer // November 2022 - Current

Flyr, Cracow, Poland (remote work)

Responsibilities/Tasks/Duties:

- Extracted components from a monolith-based application into various microservices written in Python
- Improved and expanded Fast API microservices with new functionality
- Worked on implementing PubSub and other Google Cloud services into multiple products
- Took part in designing user-management infrastructure that used Auth0
- Debugged user applications and worked on **DevOps** tasks that required **Docker**, **Kubernetes** and **Google Cloud**

Software Developer // September 2020 - November 2022 Yobota, London, UK (remote work)

Responsibilities/Tasks/Duties:

- Took part in different projects and PODs (i.e. staff API)
- Improved and expanded **Django REST Framework**-based microservices with new features and endpoints
- Took part in platform design discussions
- Co-wrote multiple microservices for the company's banking platform

Industrial placement // July 2019 - September 2020 Yobota, London, UK

Responsibilities/Tasks/Duties:

- Expanded a simulation app written in Python used to predict the behaviour of the in-house banking platform using REST APIs
- Containerized services using Heroku, AWS, Docker and Ansible
- Wrote Confluence documentation of the codebase